Nick Peihl

nickpeihl@gmail.com (760) 883-0534 http://npeihl.com

Geospatial Data Analyst and Web Developer with 10+ years experience organizing and administering spatial databases and six years building geospatial web applications using Leaflet, Mapbox, and ArcGIS JavaScript frameworks.

GitHub	nickpeihl	Twitter	nickpeihl	LinkedIn	nickpeihl

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Leaflet, Mapbox, Progressive Web Apps
GIS	ArcGIS Desktop / Server, Spatial analysis, GDAL / OGR
DATABASE	Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL / PostGIS, ArcSDE
PYTHON	ArcPy, Django, Jupyter, Pandas, Geopandas

EXPERIENCE

San Juan County

GIS Coordinator Jun 2013 - Present

San Juan County is an archipelago of small islands off the coast of Washington state. The San Juan islands are a very popular tourist destination but otherwise sparsely populated.

- Build fast and responsive geospatial web applications using progressive web app technologies
- Created Footprint Review a crowdsourcing web application for conflating GIS data
- Re-negotiated aerial photography contract to provide higher resolution imagery at no additional cost
- Supervision of all GIS department projects and staff
- Assigned role of backup IT Manager for supervision of staff and critical decision-making

Coachella Valley Association of Governments

GIS Analyst Aug 2005 - May 2013

The Coachella Valley Association of Governments (CVAG) is a municipal planning agency which administers the Coachella Valley Multiple Species Habitat Conservation Plan (CVMSHCP). The CVMSHCP is a 1.1 million acre plan to protect species habitats and ecologies.

- Designed and maintained enterprise geodatabases running on Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL/PostGIS to link geospatial data with a
 document management system
- Conducted spatial analyses to determine where and how proposed developments affect protected species habitats and natural communities
- Designed annual reports showing habitat conservation progress using spatial SQL queries
- Used Django framework to develop a data entry web application for consultantsß

VOLUNTEERING

Cascadia Users of Geospatial Open Source (CUGOS)

Contributor/Presenter Oct 2015 - Present

CUGOS provides support and ideas for users of open source geospatial software through monthly meetings, annual conferences and project sidecars.

- Core contributor to the Dropchop open source project (http://dropchop.io)
- Presentation on open source options for offline custom maps for mobile devices

EDUCATION

North Dakota State University

Sep 1999 - May 2004 Bachelor of Science - Management Information Systems / Computer Science